<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CDC Online Newsroom</title>
<description>
Welcome to the CDC Online Newsroom, a one-stop source for journalists seeking public health information. Global media and the general public can access current and archived press releases, media advisories and press briefing transcripts. While here, check out our image library, formatted releases and story ideas pages, and sign up to receive press releases and other updates by e-mail.
</description>
<link>http://www.cdc.gov/media/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.cdc.gov/media/index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<image>
<title>CDC Online Newsroom</title>
<url>http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/images/cdclogo.jpg</url>
<link>http://www.cdc.gov/media/index.html</link>
<width>95</width>
<height>61</height>
</image>
<language>en-US</language>
<webMaster>media@cdc.gov</webMaster>
<category>Health</category>
<category>Public Health</category>
<item>
<title>
Transcript for CDC Telebriefing: Updates on Zika response efforts - Transcript
</title>
<description>
Transcript for CDC Telebriefing: Updates on Zika response efforts
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640774
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640774
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 11:16:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Transcript</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Potential Laboratory-acquired Salmonella Infection at CDC - Media Statement
</title>
<description>
CDC is investigating how one of its laboratory workers who was recently diagnosed with Salmonella infection may have acquired their infection due to work they performed in a BSL-2 laboratory (a level of lab work involving pathogens that are common and treatable causes of illness).
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640993
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640993
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 15:01:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Statement</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
World Health Organization Declares Sierra Leone Free of Ebola Virus Transmission - Media Statement
</title>
<description>
CDC Spokesperson expand Facts About CDC expand Contact Media Relations expand Get Email Updates To receive email updates about this page, enter your email address: What's this?Submit Connect with CDC Media Subscribe to Media RSS Feeds Subscribe to CDC Media e-mail Syndicate Media on Your Site CDC Quick Links CDC In The News Data & Statistics Freedom of Information Act Office Public Health Image Library (PHIL) CDC 24/7 – Saving Lives. Protecting People. Saving Money Through Prevention. Learn More About How CDC Works For You… CDC>Newsroom Home>Press Materials>CDC Newsroom Releases World Health Organization Declares Sierra Leone Free of Ebola Virus Transmission Recommend on Facebook Tweet Share Twitter Facebook LinkedIn Email Digg Media Statement For Immediate Release: Saturday, November 7, 2015 Contact: Media Relations (404) 639-3286 On November 7, 2015, the World Health Organization (WHO) declared Sierra Leone free of Ebola virus transmission. This date marked 42 days (two 21-day incubation periods) from the release of the last known patient with Ebola from a Sierra Leone Ebola treatment unit (ETU).
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8639049
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8639049
</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 15:32:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Statement</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
CDC Telebriefing: New and Updated Interim Guidance for Zika virus - Media Advisory
</title>
<description>
CDC is issuing interim guidelines for preventing sexual transmission of Zika virus and updated interim guidance for health care providers caring for pregnant women and women of reproductive age with possible Zika virus exposure
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640366
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640366
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 09:46:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Advisory</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
CDC adds countries to interim travel guidance related to Zika virus - Media Statement
</title>
<description>
CDC is working with other public health officials to monitor for ongoing Zika virus? transmission. Today, CDC added the following destinations to the Zika virus travel alerts: Barbados, Bolivia, Ecuador, Guadeloupe, Saint Martin, Guyana, Cape Verde, and Samoa.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640201
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640201
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 10:31:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Statement</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
CDC issues Interim Guidelines for Preventing Sexual Transmission of Zika Virus and Updated Interim Guidelines for Health Care Providers Caring for Pregnant Women and Women of Reproductive Age with Possible Zika Virus Exposure - Media Statement
</title>
<description>
CDC has issued new interim guidance on preventing sexual transmission of Zika virus after confirming through laboratory testing, in collaboration with Dallas County Health and Human Services, the first case of Zika virus infection in a non-traveler in the continental United States during this outbreak.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640368
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640368
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:30:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Statement</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
U.S. Zika Action Plan Summit and Press Conference - Media Advisory
</title>
<description>
Hosted by CDC, the one-day Zika Action Plan Summit will bring together officials from local, state and federal jurisdictions and non-government organizations to prepare for a coordinated U.S. response to Zika.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640961
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640961
</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 16:46:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Advisory</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Enhanced Entry Airport Screening for Ebola Modified for Travelers from Guinea to the United States
</title>
<description>
On Dec. 29, 2015, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) will modify enhanced Ebola port-of-entry screening for travelers from Guinea.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8639840
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8639840
</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 14:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Statement</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Announcing the Healthcare-Associated Venous Thromboembolism Prevention Challenge Champions: Hospital Systems Saving Lives through Innovative Prevention Efforts - Press Release
</title>
<description>
The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) today recognized eight hospitals and healthcare systems as Healthcare-Associated Venous Thromboembolism (HA-VTE) Prevention Champions for their success in implementing innovative and effective ways to prevent venous thromboembolism in healthcare settings.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640967
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640967
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 16:32:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Press Release</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Superbugs threaten hospital patients - Digital Press Kit
</title>
<description>
CDC’s latest Vital Signs report urges healthcare workers to use a combination of infection control recommendations to better protect patients from healthcare-associated infections (HAIs) and antibiotic resistance.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640669
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640669
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 13:03:00 EDT</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.cdc.gov/media/images/releases/2016/p0303-superbugs-300x200px..jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
<category>Digital Press Kit</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Smoking rates for uninsured and adults on Medicaid more than twice those for adults with private health insurance - Press Release
</title>
<description>
American adults who are uninsured or on Medicaid smoke at rates more than double those for adults with private health insurance or Medicare, according to a study published by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in today’s Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report (MMWR).
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8639073
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8639073
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 13:02:00 EDT</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.cdc.gov/media/images/releases/2015/p1112-smoking-rates-300x200px.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
<category>Press Release</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Transcript for CDC Telebriefing: Guideline for Prescribing Opioids for Chronic Pain - Transcript
</title>
<description>
The release of the CDC guideline for prescribing opioids for chronic pain
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640848
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640848
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 16:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Transcript</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Continued increase in birth defect of abdominal wall - Press Release
</title>
<description>
Cases of a serious birth defect of the abdominal wall called gastroschisis continues to increase over time, according to a report in CDC’s Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640175
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640175
</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:01:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Press Release</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
JAMA’s publication of five perceptive and practical opinions - Media Statement
</title>
<description>
In our effort to reach primary care providers, the respected voice of JAMA is instrumental. We are encouraged by JAMA’s publication of five perceptive and practical opinions that give prescribers insight into the need for and application of the CDC Guideline for Prescribing Opioids for Pain according to their patients’ needs.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640846
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8640846
</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:31:00 EDT</pubDate>
<category>Media Statement</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Zika Virus - Vital Signs: Zika and Pregnancy - Digital Press Kit
</title>
<description>
In past Zika outbreaks, most people have not gotten sick, so people may not even know they are infected. Based on current knowledge, the greatest risk for complications from Zika is to a pregnant woman’s fetus.
</description>
<link>
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8641008
</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">
http://www2c.cdc.gov/podcasts/download.asp?af=h&f=8641008
</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 13:02:00 EDT</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.cdc.gov/media/images/dpk/2016/dpk-zika/mosquito-300x200px.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
<category>Digital Press Kit</category>
</item>